technicaltextile.net 2019-03-22

# Privacy Policy - TechnicalTextile.net – B2B Technical Textile Portal

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 25th May 2018

At Technicaltextile.net we understand the care you assign towards usage and sharing of your information and we appreciate your unwavering trust that we will do so carefully. This notice describes our privacy policy. ****

The  Fibre2Fashion Private Limited   (hereinafter collectively referred to as "fibre2fashion.com", "TECHNICALTEXTILE.NET", "We", "Us" or "Our") , the owner and promoter of [www.Technicaltextile.net](http://www.technicaltextile.net/) Privacy Policy describes how we collect, use, and disclose information when you visit or use our website ("Site") or any other website or mobile application that links to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the "Services"). By visiting Technicaltextile.net or using our Services you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Notice.

### **Some key terms**

In our Privacy Policy, when we refer to: 

  * "Customers" (hereinafter collectively referred to as "You", "Your", "User"), we mean our customers who use our Services, including visitors to our sites. 
  * "Your Content", we mean any information provided by you as a result of usage of our services

This policy covers the below mentioned: 

  * What personal information about Customers does Technicaltextile.net collect?
  * Use of Information
  * How we use Cookies and Similar Technologies?
  * Sharing of Information
  * Storage and Transfer of Personal Information
  * Security of your information
  * Advertising and links to other sites
  * What rights you have?
  * Privacy of Children
  * California Do Not Track
  * Questions/Changes to policy

## What personal information about Customers does Technicaltextile.net collect? 

The information we learn from customers can be broadly classified into four categories as mentioned below, such information helps us personalize and continually improve our services and hence your experience: 

**Information You Provide Us:**   
We receive and store any information you enter on our site or give us in any other way. For example, during sign up you provide us with name, , business information, including but not limited to address, email, designation, phone number and URL. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features. We use the information that you provide for purposes such as responding to your requests, to connect with prospective buyers and sellers, and communicating with you. 

**Information we collect automatically:**   
We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many sites, we use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses Technicaltextile.net or advertisements served by or on behalf of Technicaltextile.net on other sites. 

**Via Mobile or Smartphones:**   
When you download or use our apps, we may receive certain information. For example, information about your location or the unique identifier for your device . We may use this information to provide you with location-based services, such as advertising and personalization. You may restrict the permissions you provide to our apps, however by doing so you may not be able to access the full features of our apps. 

**Information from Other Sources:**   
Technicaltextile.net Site may include buttons, tools, or information that link to other third-party services (for example, a Facebook "Comment" button). We may collect information about your use of these features. In addition, when you see or interact with these buttons, tools, or information, or view a TECHNICALTEXTILE.NET web page or App containing them, some information from your browser may automatically be sent to the other company. Please read that company’s privacy policy for more information. You can refer to the list of third parties here.

##  Use of Information 

We may use your personal information including but not limited to the following purposes:

  * To administer your use of our Services 
  * To facilitate buyer and supplier connect. 
  * To better understand your needs and interests 
  * To better understand and improvise our products and services
  * To facilitate your use and personalizing your experience on the Site 
  * To serve you relevant ads
  * To book your ads that we will display on website and apps
  * To respond to your inquiries or fulfilling your requests for information about our Services 
  * To provide you with information about our Services and sending you information and materials from TECHNICALTEXTILE.NET including marketing communication 
  * To help you address problems with the Site, including any technical problems 
  * To Process online job application, you have applied for 
  * To detect and prevent identity theft, fraud, and other potentially illegal acts as well as protecting the integrity of the website 
  * To respond to subpoenas, court orders, or judicial processes 
  * To provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety 
  * To resolve disputes and troubleshoot problems 
  * To help with any investigations or complaints 
  * To provide you with relevant information or Services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you based on previous interactions, where you have consented to be contacted 

We use the information we collect in a variety of ways. Generally, using all of the above mentioned, and similar type tools, we may collect, aggregate, and use information from or about you such as data about the type of browser and operating system used, which web pages you view, the time and duration or you visits to our Site, the search queries you may use on the Site, whether you clicked on any advertisements, whether you have clicked on any links in any e-mails sent from us, or third-parties on our behalf and whether you have chosen to opt-out of certain services or information sharing. 

## How we use Cookies and Similar Technologies?

Cookies are bits of electronic information that a website may transfer to a visitor's computer to identify specific information about the visitor's visits to a website. The Site uses a browser feature known as a cookie, which assigns a unique identification to your computer, in case you do not wish us to collect such information kindly refer to our cookie policy to opt out. You can access the details of our **Cookie Policy here** _ _ **.**__

If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the instructions for your file management software to locate the file or directory that store cookies. 

Alternatively, you may wish to visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) which contains comprehensive information on how to manage cookies on a wide variety of browsers. However, please note that if you disable the use of cookies on your computer, some functionalities of our Services will not work.

## Sharing of Information

Technicaltextile.net provides your personal information to third parties who are obligated to use the personal information that Technicaltextile.net shares with them for the purpose of provision of their services to us in order to help us run our business. These third parties include but are not limited to business partners, suppliers, sub-contractors, advertisers & advertising networks, analytics & search engine providers, payment providers. We may also share with third parties aggregate information or information that does not personally identify you. Should you require more details on third parties we work with or have any questions around it, please **click here** to know more about the third parties we work with. 

For example, we use several payment gateways (one among which is HDFC bank) to manage our payments, but we reserve the right to change this service provider at any time for any reason.. Your credit card information will also be subject to our payment processor’s privacy policy in addition to ours. PLEASE READ THE PRIVACY POLICY ON THE WEBSITE OF ANY PAYMENT PROCESSOR THAT YOU ARE DIRECTED TO REGARDING THE USE, STORAGE AND PROTECTION OF YOUR CREDIT CARD INFORMATION BEFORE SUBMITTING ANY CREDIT CARD INFORMATION. 

hen you make a charge, we shall display a completed charge screen. This is your electronic receipt. You should print or save this electronic receipt for your records. YOU REPRESENT AND WARRANT THAT YOU HAVE THE LEGAL RIGHT TO USE ANY CREDIT CARDS, DEBIT CARDS OR OTHER PAYMENT MEANS USED TO INITIATE ANY TRANSACTION.

We may also share your personal information in the following circumstances

  * When we are required to provide information in response to a subpoena, court order, or other applicable law or legal process. 
  * When we have a good faith belief that the disclosure is necessary to prevent or respond to fraud, defend our apps or websites against attacks, or protect the property and safety of Technicaltextile.net, our customers and users, or the public. 
  * If we merge with or are acquired by another company, sell a Technicaltextile.net website, app, or business unit, or if all or a substantial portion of our assets are acquired by another company. In those cases, your information will likely be one of the assets that is transferred. 

There are several places within the Site and our Apps that allow you to post comments or submit Your Content for others to see. We will display your Personal Information in your account and elsewhere on our Services according to your subscription plan. Any information you choose to provide should reflect how much you want others to know about you. Please consider carefully what information you disclose in your profile page and your desired level of anonymity. You can review and revise your profile information at any time. To remove Your Content, you have shared on the Site or our Apps, you may use the same features (available on the Site/Apps) to do so. In case you have any query regarding removal and or deletion of such contact you can write to us at **[privacy@technicaltextile.net](mailto:privacy@technicaltextile.net)** .

## Storage and Transfer of Personal Information

Your personal information and files are stored on Technicaltextile.net’s servers and the servers of companies we hire to provide services to us. Your personal information may be transferred across national borders because we have servers located in India and Singapore, and the companies we hire to help us run our business may be located in different countries around the world.

The information that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored in, a country outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. The laws in some countries may not provide as much legal protection for your information as in the EEA. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of your information transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

## Security of your information

We understand that the security of your personal information is important. We provide reasonable administrative, technical, and physical security controls to protect your personal information. Among other initiatives that we take to maintain security of your data, we also utilize encryption of personal data and strict access controls. At the same time, it is important for you to protect against unauthorized access to your password and to your computer. Be sure to sign off when finished using a shared computer. However, despite our efforts, no security controls are 100% effective and Technicaltextile.net cannot ensure or warrant the security of your personal information. 

## Advertising and links to other sites

We display interest-based advertising on both our sites and unaffiliated sites  using information you make available to us when you interact with our sites, apps or services. Interest-based ads, also sometimes referred to as personalized or targeted ads, are displayed to you based on information from activities , your interaction with our Services and visiting sites that contain Technicaltextile.net content or ads. 

We use cookies, web beacons and other technologies (collectively, "cookies and similar technologies"). Cookies enable us to learn about what ads you see, what ads you click, and other actions you take on our sites and other sites. This allows us to provide you with more useful and relevant ads. For example, by knowing what ads you are shown we can be careful not to show you the same ones repeatedly. For more information about the use of cookies and similar technologies for interest-based advertising, please refer to our **cookie policy here**.

Some of the functionality on our Services may be provided by third parties that are not affiliated with Technicaltextile.net. These entities may collect or receive certain information about your use of our Services and your activities over time and across different websites, including through the use of cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we are not responsible for, third-party cookies, web beacons, or other tracking technologies. Technicaltextile.net is not responsible for the privacy practices of these entities. In addition, our Services may contain links to other websites not operated or controlled by us. Such websites are not under our control and we are not responsible for their privacy policies or practices. If you provide any personal information through any such third-party website, we recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and practices of that third party.

You may choose to enable or log in to our Services via various online services like Google, including social networking services like Facebook, LinkedIn etcetera. Our services also may enable you to access social networking services such as Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn, or Google (collectively, "Social Network") directly or indirectly through our Services.

When you link a Social Network account to our Apps or log into our Services using your Social Network account, we may collect relevant information necessary to enable our Services to access that Social Network and your data contained within that Social Network. We may share your information with the operator of that Social Network to facilitate or enhance delivery of that Social Network or other services to you. A Social Network may provide us with access to certain information that you have provided to them, and we will use, store, and disclose such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Additionally, a Social Network may collect personal information and information about your use of our Site or Services automatically. The manner in which a Social Network collects, uses, stores, and discloses your information is governed by the policies of such third parties and Technicaltextile.net shall have no liability or responsibility for the privacy practices or other actions of any Social Network that may be enabled within its Services.   

## What rights you have?

_Right to be informed_ :   
You are entitled to know whether we hold your personal information and the purpose your personal data is processed for. 

_Right of access_ :   
You are entitled to know the categories of your personal data being processed, the purposes of such processing, and the details of third parties to whom the data may have been disclosed. For more details please refer to the list of **third parties here** . 

_Right to rectification_ :   
You are entitled to correct / update your personal information available with us. 

_Right to erasure_ : 

You are entitled to get your data erased from our databases. Please note that we might need to retain certain information about you for reasons including but not limited to legal, internal business and fraud prevention. We will retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide you with the services you are eligible to use and as needed to comply with our legal obligations and enforce our agreements. ****

_Right to data portability_ :   
You are entitled to obtain and reuse your personal data. You can either obtain the data from us or, in turn, provide it to a third party (if you so wish), or ask us to transfer your personal data directly to a third party. 

_Right to object / restrict processing or both_ :   
You have a right to object / restrict the processing of your data in some circumstances, including where the data is inaccurate (for the period during which we are verifying the data), the data is no longer required in light of the purpose of processing, or in connection with direct marketing (you can prevent / discontinue marketing communications to you by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your personal data), or by utilizing opt-out mechanisms in the emails we send you. 

In the above cases, we will retain minimum personal data to note that you opted out from being contacted again. For raising requests pertaining to the above-mentioned rights, please write to us at privacy@technicaltextile.net. Please note some of the rights mentioned herein may not be available as we are designing the technical capabilities to comply with such requests; having said the above Technicaltextile.net will do its best to resolve your request to the best of its ability. 

## Privacy of Children

We recognize the importance of children's safety and privacy. We do not request, or knowingly collect, any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 18. Technicaltextile.net is very sensitive to privacy issues regarding children. By visiting this Site or providing your personal information to one of our call-centre operators or live chat representatives or starting your free trial or signing up or logging in you are claiming yourself to be 18 years of age or above. 

If you believe that any child under the age of 18 has posted any personal information anywhere on our website, please contact us immediately at [privacy@technicatltexile.net](mailto:privacy@technicatltexile.net) and provide as much information as you can to help us locate and delete the personal information. 

If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child or any other child under the age of 18 has provided us with personal information, he or she should write to us at [privacy@technicaltextile.net](mailto:privacy@technicaltextile.net) ____

## California Do Not Track

Technicaltextile.net does not have a mechanism in place for responding to browser "do not track" signals or other similar mechanisms used to limit collection of information for use in Online Behavioural Advertising. There currently is no consensus among industry participants as to what "Do Not Track" means in this context. Therefore, like many websites and online services, the Services do not alter their practices when they receive a "Do Not Track" signal from a visitor's browser. To find out more about "Do Not Track," please visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com.](http://www.allaboutdnt.com./)

## Questions/Changes to policy

Technicaltextile.net welcomes your comments regarding this Privacy Policy. If you believe that we have not adhered to this Policy or If you have questions or concerns with respect to our Privacy Policy, please write to us at [privacy@technicaltextile.net](mailto:privacy@technicaltextile.net)

## Third Party List

**Purpose** | **Third party Sites** | **Description**  
---|---|---  
Sales CRM | Zoho CRM | Application used for Customer Relationship Management  
Email Marketing | Mail Chimp | Used for sending e-mailers to target base  
Netcore - Pepipost  
Recommind  
Email Verification | Email Checker | For verifying if the emails are active  
Traffic Analytics | Google Analytics | For analysing traffic on various sections of Technical Textiles  
AW Stats  
Accounting | Tally | For account keeping & generating sales invoice  
Server Hosting | Amazon Web Service | For hosting of TT's server on cloud
